CV

Sixten H. Schelin

Fogdevägen 5A no. 1202, 371 40 Karlskrona, Sweden sixtensch@gmail.com 070–799 97 83

Summary

I am a competent software and game developer enrolled at the Blekinge Institute of Technology where I'm working on my masters as a civil engineer in game engine development and computer systems programming. A focus on quality of service/product, an intuitive, creative, and calculating identity, a focus on flexibility over set-in-stone principles, as well as a personal obsession over learning and self-improvement form the basis of my character and work ethic, whereas my own personal nature makes me well suitable for work both on my lonesome and with a team of coworkers. I graduated top of my class studying programming and computer technology in high school and was granted a scholarship for academic excellence among my peers.

I have several years of non-professional experience as a programmer and I am employable working with C++, C, and C#, as well as being competent in other languages with a proven ability to pick up skillsets within information and computer technology very quickly. As a team leader and project manager I have shown excellent proficiency over the years, where I put a focus on whole-team productivity, cooperation, effective task delegation, social/individual understanding, and mutual respect. I am a firm believer in that all tasks can be performed smoothly and efficiently where intuition and creative problem solving is applied!

Experience

2023-2024 – Lab Assistant and Examiner in ARM/x86 ASM, Blekinge Institute of Technology I work until recently for the university where I study, being one of two principal lab session supervisors for a computer engineering course. I assisted students, mainly in their 2nd but also 3rd years, with programming assignments built around ARM and x86 assembly, in addition to acting as examiner and grading assignments after verbal presentations.

2021-2023 – **Teacher and Lecturer in C++ programming, Blekinge Institute of Technology** I worked for BTH assisting younger students in learning C++ programming, designing challenges and problems for practice, holding lectures focused on assisting students with the psychological challenges of learning complex programming languages, and assisting teachers with designing the course or processing students' experiences and feedback.

2015-2017 - Chef and waiter, Vellinge Gästis

Worked as a cook and generalist with a team of coworkers at a local family restaurant in Vellige, where I among other tasks prepared foodstuffs in-kitchen, worked as a waiter among customers, and cooked food on display at special events. Frequently called in during odd hours and often worked overtime during late nights, holidays and weekends.

2015 - Chef (Internship), Vellinge Gästis

Mostly same as above, whereas I during my internship performed slightly more trivial or repetitive work but quickly got entrusted with larger and more critical responsibilities.

Education

2020-present **BTH Karlskrona** Civil engineering in game and software technology

2017-2020 LBS Lund Technology (Product Development), video game programming

2007-2017 Framtidskompassen Primary schooling

Language skills

Swedish – First language. Born and raised in Vellinge, Sweden.

English – Experienced and fluent in both speech and writing. Neutral and easy-to-understand American-esque accent.

Software skills

Unity Well versed (non-enterprise)

Git Well versed
Godot Some familiarity
Microsoft Office Well versed

Microsoft Visual Studio & VSC Well versed (non-enterprise)

Google Online Suite Well versed
Adobe CS6 Photoshop Well versed
Inkscape Some familiarity

Autodesk Maya Some familiarity (non-enterprise)

Other software competences: Blender, Aseprite, Logic Pro, Propellerhead Reason, Bitwig Studio, Unreal Engine 4, SketchUp, etc.

I am comfortable working with both Windows, Linux, and Mac OSX machines, preferring the former where I have the most extensive experience. I have programming experience working with OpenGL, and DirectX within C/C++ engine development as well as other C++ and C# services such as XNA or Windows Forms. I have some experience using other languages such as Rust, LUA, Python, Beeflang, Java, and Intel x86 as well as ARM assembly.

Sixten H. Schelin 2001-10-13

Fogdevägen 5A, 1202 371 40 Karlskrona (Since July 30th, 2020)

070-799 97 83 sixtensch@gmail.com